Leah: Agile and Scrum
Scrum is a framework of Agile
so the strengths and weaknesses
for each one is very similar.
There are further ones that are specific
to Scrum, but the following ones we are
going to look at here are the main ones.
Let’s first look at the Strengths
Chris: Flexible and adaptable.
Because the requirements do not need
to be defined at the beginning of the
project, changes can take place quickly
and easily in Agile and Scrum development.
Leah: Creative and innovative-Team
members are more creative and
innovative as there is more freedom
for change due to it being flexible
and adaptable with less rigid planning.
Chris: Reduced time-to-market-Due
to the shorter start-up time,
frequent reviews, and the iterative
approach, Agile and Scrum developments
have quicker product releases.
Leah: Higher productivity of
team and improved quality.
Because Agile and Scrum prioritises
requirements there is less risk that
the project specification will increase.
Higher productivity and improved
quality are also due to the team
being more focused, self-managed,
responsible for own tasks, and having
job satisfaction due to frequent
iterations and completions of tasks.
Chris: Customer satisfaction-Customers
are more satisfied as they participate
in the development process, their
feedback is valued, and they can see
where this is being used in the product.
Leah: Organisation transparency-Agile
and Scrum enables other employees [who
could also be stakeholders] within the
organisation to be included in the project
which supports partnerships and trust.
Chris: Now let’s look at the Weaknesses
Training needed-If Agile and or
Scrum haven’t been used before then
there would need to be training
so all the team members are
comfortable with the principles,
ceremonies, practices, and roles.
Leah: Complexity of skills
required-Depending on the project there
would be a need of a mix of roles and
technical ability such as Developers,
Testers, Designers, and a Scrum master.
Chris: Organisation - initial change
needs-If the organisation does not
support Agile or Scrum, then the
team would be working in isolation.
Less understanding and support would
be given from the wider organisation
to the team members which could
result in ‘scope-creep’ and an
increased workload for the Scrum
Master whose role as a ‘Servant
Leader’ would be to protect the team.
Leah: Not suitable for certain types
of projects-Agile and Scrum are not
suitable for certain types of projects,
especially larger scale ones which
require a high level of certainty so
a lot of planning would be required.
Chris: Agile is the opposite of Waterfall,
its more flexible, good for urgent
projects, higher level of complexity, with
varying tolerance for change and bugs.
It is often used when the team
needs to know something new,
such as for Apps, games, etc.
Companies that have used
Agile include ‘Philips’,
‘VistaPrint’, ‘JP Morgan Chase’.
Scrum can be used for projects
that need flexibility as it can
easily adapt to unexpected changes.
It is a good framework to use for
projects that are urgent, complex need
quick deliverables, and a team who are
already comfortable with this framework.
Leah: Examples of Scrum projects include
‘Saab Defense’ to develop a fighter jet
for mission critical software, ‘Intronis
online backup services’ for increased
call centre productivity, and ‘Yahoo!’
Who use scrum for over 100 Software teams.